# **KEVIN ADRIAN RODRIGUEZ RUIZ**

Chemical engineer, software developer

## About me

BSc. in Chemical engineer and MEng. in computing with more than five years of experience in software development.

Self-disciplined person and excited about interdisciplinary projects aimed to solve life-science problems by using computational approaches. I enjoy making scientific work easier and more accessible.

# Computing skills

Java, Javascript, Node.js, Python, Amazon Web Services, Git, Reactjs, Spring Framework, Django, Postgresql, web applications, NoSQL databases, Scrum, Docker, VS Code, Intellij Idea, Aspen Plus.

## Languages

Spanish (native) English (fluent) French (basic)

### Contact

Bogotá, Colombia. 111156 (+57 1) 6698229 (+57) 3057052399



karodriguezr@unal.edu.co



<u>LinkedIn profile</u>



GitHub public repositories

## **Interests**

Systems biology, computer science, chemical process simulation, mathematical modelling, bioinformatics, data science, optimization, software development.

### Education

2016 - 2019	M. Eng. in Systems Engineering and Computing Universidad Nacional de Colombia (Colombia)
2018 – 2019	Exchange Student in the MSc in Advanced Catalysis and Molecular Modelling Universitat de Girona (Spain)
2009 – 2015	Bachelor's degree in Chemical Engineering Universidad Nacional de Colombia (Colombia)

## Short courses

- Advanced Separation Operations. Separation Technologies in
   Biorefineries
   International Chair of Engineering, Universidad Nacional de Colombia
- 2017 Introduction to innovation and the use of technology for learning International School, Universidad Nacional de Colombia
- 2014 **Software maintenance, evolution, and re-engineering**International Chair of Engineering, Universidad Nacional de Colombia

# Academic projects

- + CAMD. Master's final work. Computational tool to design environment-friendly solvents for liquid-liquid separation by applying Computer Aided Molecular Design (CAMD) techniques. The program uses multi-objective optimization, group-contribution methods and databases mining algorithms. Technologies: Java, Mongodb. ☑
- + ANSEP. Design and development of Astrocyte Neuron Simulation Environment Platform. Web platform for the analysis of genome-scale metabolic models related to the study of neurodegenerative diseases. Technologies: Python, R, Django, Reactjs, Docker, Postgresql. Project

- funded by the *Pontificia Universidad Javeriana* and the *Administrative Department of Science, Technology and Innovation (Colciencias*).
- + Rescurves. Open source MS Excel Add-in to automate the plotting of three-dimensional diagrams representing the residue curves maps of quaternary systems. Technologies: C#, VSTO Add-ins. ☑

## **Employment**

#### GNB Sudameris Bank (2020)

+ Java developer. Development of financial web services consumed by the mobile applications. Technologies: Java, Rxjava, Spring Boot, Amazon Web Services.

### Amaris Consulting (2019 - 2020)

+ Full-stack developer. Development of web services and user interfaces for the management of insurance policies. Technologies: Reactjs, Redux, Serverless Framework, Amazon Web Services.

### Software Colombia SAS (2015 – 2018)

- + Full-Stack developer. Design, development a web platform for massive email marketing platform. Technologies: Java, Spring Framework, Nodejs, Gradle, Amazon Web Services.
- + Software developer. Design, development and support of desktop applications signing information digitally, encrypting data and storing files in the cloud. Technologies: Javascript, Java and JavaFX.